just a guy that, you know, I've been to
four conference championship games, two
on the NFC, two on the AFC. Um I've been
to two Super Bowls, 1-1. So that kind of
um experience, I think, can can boast
well for for a program that's right
there, honestly. Um two years ago, you
guys were just at the NC Championship
game. So, um, obviously the the culture
here is set in knowing how to win, just
kind of just that finishing piece and
like I said, just the versatility up and
down the line of scrimmage, um,
tenacity, length, size, and then again
being able to rush and and make impact
in the pass in the run game.
>> So, this is kind of a two-part question
that's not really related, but I'm guess
sneak in the second one. First of all,
how do you feel with your knee and the
recovery a couple years out now? That's
one. Then, secondly, you talked about
their versatility. What allows you to
because you I saw a lot of rushers
inside. So, what allows you to be an
effective rusher inside?
>> Yeah. So, my knee is perfectly fine. Um
I feel great. I think being two years
removed now. Uh any maybe small little
hiccup here or there, I think will be
gone. And again, like you got some time
before the season starts to really iron
out anything else. So, but overall, I
feel great. I feel just as good as or
even better than before I got hurt. Um,
and then as far as like what allows me
to be versatile, I think it would just
be my length. Um, size and there I just
feel comfortable rushing really anywhere
honestly. Uh, anywhere where I can get a
a one-on-one um, and you know, any
matchup I feel very comfortable in. I I
did it in college. I've done it in
college. I did it when I got drafted to
Houston. Um, I did it with the Niners. I
did it with the Chiefs. So, it was just
something that um, was I I found fun,
honestly. Um, I think it's really fun to
be able to just rush anywhere. So, uh,
just kind of just kind of continue to
build that over my career.
>> Thank you,
>> David Aldridge.
>> Hey, Charles, welcome. Uh,
I've been asking everybody this morning
that have come from these really
successful teams why they're here
[laughter] because because you could
have either stayed where you were or
gone to another successful team,
>> but you chose to come to to this place
that's building. I mean, they had
success a year ago with your wonder what
what what was the attraction?
>> I think the attraction was just the plan
and and it starts from the top. Um, Adam
Peters AP is just I've known him since
when I was with the Ners. So, um, I know
that he understands exactly what it's
supposed to look like. And, um, um,
Coach Quinn, um, he's had success
everywhere he's been at, especially with
defensive linemen and how he's deployed
defensive linemen up front and moved
them around and really put them in
positions to be at their best. Um, Coach
Henderson, another guy that's had
success at the highest level. He's won a
Super Bowl. Um, he knows also how to
deploy defensive line, put them in their
best skill set. Had many conversations
with him and I just love their plan for
me honestly. Um, I had a before I
signed, I had a conversation with the
entire staff, um, the defense um, and AP
and coach Quinn and they illustrated a
plan for me that I feel like is going to
um, get me back exactly where I was at
um, two seasons ago. um the success that
I had um I don't think it's farfetched
or far gone at all. I feel great
bodywise. I just think um the plan that
they have for me is just really going to
expose my strengths and put me in
positions to rush uh put me in positions
to play the run at high level and I love
that. And then also, man, if you just
look at the other guys that they brought
in, you know, this listen this this I
I've been in the league for eight years
now, and a lot of these guys I know and
I know them personally. Um there's a lot
of really really good players that they
brought in, really good players already
on this team. So, um I don't I don't I
wouldn't be surprised if you know
there's big strides here this year.
>> Thank you,
>> Donna.
>> Hi, Charles. How you doing?
>> Thank you.
>> Um you talked about um you coming from
win a lot of winning uh so that'll be
great for the commanders but uh you
talked about success what does success
look like to you as you come to
Washington and and entrench yourself
into this defense
>> uh success is just starts off team you
know um winning you just winning is fun
you know and then when you have a
defensive system that's being built here
that um is going to let guys just rip
and roar and and get after it up front.
Um, the defense is going to be a big
part of the winning. So, um, I think
success is again, like I said, starts
off with team and then individual
success. Everybody here is going to have
a plan and a role and that role is going
to be able to elevate their game in
order to feel like they're making an
impact on the team. So, you put those
things together, it's like a big happy
family.
>> And you talked about culture. It sounds
like culture is important to you. As
[clears throat] you come to the
commanders and where where you came
from, could you talk a little bit more
about culture and what that looks like
and means to you?
>> Yeah. So, culture is a is is the
building block of any organization that
you're in. Uh we just so happen to be in
the football organization. So, just the
standard of how things are like guys not
being laid. That's kind of number one
flagship kind of deal. Um respecting
everybody. Uh being honest and
straightforward. I think uh in the NFL
that can sometimes not be the thing. But
when you're with people that are this
genuine just as individuals regardless
of the space that we're in, I think that
brings a comfort level for players that
you know they they they can just be
themselves and they can just really dial
in on the playbook, dial in on their
nutrition, dial in on um their their
their their continuous recovering rehab
um to keep their body in tip-top shape.
And I think when you have guys who all
buy in and believe in those core values,
I think that's how you instill good
culture and it just kind of thrives off
and into into games.
>> Oh, welcome again to the Burgundy and
Gold.
>> Yes, ma'am. Thank you,
>> Ben.
>> Hey, Charles. Um, also welcome to to
town. You talked about you really like
the plan that they had for you. Just to
drill down on a little bit, is that more
like kind of like where you they see you
lining up? Is that kind of what you're
talking about?
>> Yeah. So, they broke it down in the run
game and they broke it down in the pass
game. And, um, you know, it's been a
little while since I've been in a under
front. So, um, just understanding like,
hey, the advantageous positions I'll be
in, um, it all just made sense. Like I
said, this is my eighth year in the
league, so I can quickly kind of
understand somebody having a plan and
somebody just not having a plan. When
you do have a plan, that breeds success.
So just having a plan in the run game
and how it'll be a lot of individual
one-on-one blocks, how it'll be a lot of
just wouldn't say easy because in the
NFL nothing's easy, but where you're not
going to be in position where you could
be not in an advant advantage, you know,
and then in the pass game, um rushing
inside, I I I I can't wait honestly um
to be in a system where, you know, they
believe in the fourman, fiveman rush, um
games, twist stunts, and you're going to
be with guys like uh my boy Oway, um
Kavon and um JK and Payne and um Dorance
when he gets right. And so I mean I just
listed a whole bunch of guys who have
done very well in other places.
Obviously Payne was here his whole
career, but other guys have done very
well in other places and you know just
know how they know how to rush. And then
Leo, my boy Leo is here. So uh yeah,
man. The plan is just it's it's I I love
it. I like it. It's rejuvenating. Um and
I can't wait to get going.
And I was going to take advantage of you
knowing uh Leo to ask about him. What
what do you think ultimately he's going
to kind of bring both on the field and
into the locker room?
>> Yeah, Leo's a class A teammate first and
foremost. Um and uh Leo is a physical
physical physical player. Um you know,
when you when you watch Leo's tape,
you're going to see that he takes no
prisoner. Um he's versatile. Um Leo's a
great blitzer. Uh I think Leo has really
really good coverage skills. I know
people might be sleep on that, but Leo
can run with the best of him, you know.
So, um, Leo just he can be he can play
anywhere. He's played on the edge. He's
played obviously in the box as a backer.
He's been a blitzer. He's been a spy.
Um, he has great speed. And so, in the
locker room as well, he's just a very
high energy, positive guy. I've never
I've never seen Leo mad or have any uh
fuss with teammates. So, I think just
that good energy he's going to bring in
the locker room. And again, Leo's been
what, three Super Bowls or two or three,
what I mean? Just as much as I have. So
that championship pedigree as well as a
as a young player too.
>> Awesome. Thank you [clears throat]
>> Andy.
>> Hi Charles. Welcome to Washington.
>> Thank you.
>> So I just asked um Kavon this question
as well. How would you describe your
game and what what you would be
bringing? What would we see on a game
day from you?
>> Um a Swiss Army knife is I think the
best way to to describe it. Um I can
play the four eye. I've done that in in
in my in my career. Um, I can play a
five, I can play a six, I can play a
nine. If they ever had asked me to drop,
I've done that. Um, and then I can rush
from um from anywhere on the field. I
can I can rush the center. I can rush
two eye, three, four, five, six, nine.
Like, I've I've there's been no place on
the field where I haven't rushed. So,
just being able to be in a position
where, hey, this week, Charles, we want
you to just we want you to be rushing
the center. You know, we're going to
have other guys rushing three, but this
week we want you to rush center. want
you should push pocket or whatever the
case may be cuz our edge guys you going
to have that you going to have o you
going to have Kavon you going to have
Dorance you going to have all that
deployed so anything from center guard
and out um on that third down kind of
ordeal I think is something I can take
advantage of and and be a presence here
that can elevate the defense
>> and you've definitely shared and of
course we we know as well your your
champ kind of the championship pedigree
the team that [clears throat] you've
been a part of. So, can you share a bit
about what you've seen like what are
some of those keys of this what this is
what consistently successful teams do?
>> Discipline. Discipline. I think when you
have a a disciplined football team that
doesn't hurt themselves, penalties,
pre-sap penalties, maybe just
extracurricular like man, if the guy's
going down, you don't need an extra
shove. Maybe in between the whistles
100%. But like just the extra stuff. Um,
you know, it gets chippy out there and
you know, don't be the the last guy that
the ref sees and uh and then if coach
says do this technique, just do that
technique. You know, obviously you're
going to be a football player at the end
of the day, but just being disciplined.
Like everybody here wants to win. So,
and I've already seen here that they
want to win, but they're going to put in
a a skill set that each individual can
be really, really good. So, I feel like
they have a plan for everybody. And
that's another key to success is having
a role for everybody, sticking to it,
and not really like um pivoting off of
that. Um with the two teams that have
I've had the most success with the
Niners and the Chiefs, that was the
biggest thing that I took from it.
Number one being that discipline.
>> Thank you so much and welcome again.
>> Thank you.
>> All right. Thanks, Charles. Appreciate
it.
>> Appreciate y'all.
>> Thanks, everybody.
>> Recording stopped.